Karim Languedoc

312-771-5283

karimlanguedoc@outlook.com

Chicago, IL

Summary

Highly experienced and self-motivated native iOS developer with many apps featured in the App Store. Additional experience developing native Android as well as Full-Stack web apps. Strong track record of delivering clean, quality code and top performing products on time and on budget. Proven ability to work independently as well as part of a team. Well versed in agile development methodology.

Experience

Sr. iOS Engineer

Punchkick Interactive Inc., Chicago IL - January 2016 - January 2017

At Punchkick, I built and maintained many apps using Objective-c and Swift. I utilized third party services, tools and SDKs such as Jira, Confluence and GitLab for project and code management, CocoaPods for dependency management, Google Firebase for their realtime database functionality and UrbanAirship for push notifications. I utilized git via terminal on a daily basis and conducted regular peer programming sessions, daily code reviews and merge requests.

One of two developers that built the official Petsmart app from the ground up which allows pet owners to book grooming, training and pet hotel appointments. We collaborated with with Petsmart's engineers in order to have the proper API endpoints exposed. This app has been featured in the App Store. I am also one of two developers that worked on the official AskPetMD app that allows pet owners to submit their pets symptoms to real vets.

One of two developers that built the official Copa America Centenario 2016 app from the ground up. This app is a must have for soccer fans. The app was the #2 sports app in the U.S App Store and #1 in four different latin app stores shortly after it launched. This app has been featured in the App Store.

One of two developers that worked on the Allstate Digital Locker app, currently available in the app store. I am also one of two developers that worked on and maintained the Allstate Good-ride app.

Maintained 36 different Chicago Tribune station apps such as WGN News and Fox News, all currently available in the app store.

Karim Languedoc

312-771-5283

karimlanguedoc@outlook.com

iOS Engineer & Android Engineer ComPsych Corporation, Chicago IL - March 2014 - January 2016

I was the primary mobile developer responsible for building and maintaining the company's native iOS and Android apps as well as customized versions of our EAP and FMLA websites and services for many of our fortune 500 clients.

Chicago, IL

I lead a team of four engineers to successfully overhaul our most popular sites and services with a much needed responsive design leveraging Twitter's Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery.

I lead a team of four engineers tasked with implementing Rest APIs in order to provide our customers with a richer, more native mobile experience.

Utilized git via terminal on a daily basis to conduct code reviews and merge requests. Participate in weekly stand ups.

iOS Engineer Branchfire Inc., Chicago IL - April 2012 - November 2013

At Branchfire, I had the privilege of working along side many amazing people on our flagship product, iAnnotate PDF. iAnnotate is a productivity app that allows people to mark-up and share documents easily on an iPad. I have made significant contributions to this product over the last two years by adding amazing new features, enhancing existing features and functionality or fixing bugs. Some of the features that i have implemented include:

Wrist Guard - A feature that allows our users to wrest their palm on the iPad while creating or marking up documents.

News/Notification - A feature that allows our users to remain updated on Branchfire related news and promotions.

Airdrop - A feature that allows our users to share original and marked up documents directly with our users on supported iPad models.

Karim Languedoc

312-771-5283

karimlanguedoc@outlook.com

Chicago, IL

Text To Speech - A feature that allows our users to select text on documents and have it spoken out via Apple's AVSpeechSynthesizer API available on iOS 7 devices.

UI/UX Updates - Significant updates to the user interface and user experience, primarily in version 2.5 and version 3.0.

Lead the development of the official Branchfire website. Handling both front and backend of the development process, we successfully launched a secure website that also allowed our commercial and licensed SDK users to manage their online accounts.

Actively worked on our iAnnotate SDK, allowing developers to use our annotation technology to power their own apps.

Software Engineer Lockheed Martin, Department of Defense, Fort Knox KY August 2011 - December 2011

Headquartered in Bethesda, Maryland, Lockheed Martin is a global security and aerospace company that employs approximately 98,000 people worldwide and is principally engaged in the research, design, development, manufacture, integration and sustainment of advanced technology systems, products and services.

Skills

Objective-C, Swift 3, MVC, MVVM, Continuous Integration, Git, Jira, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, PHP, Python

Education

Andrews University, Berrien Springs MI

Computer Science
Business Management